[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 15]
[제15화]
Demonic energy?
마기다
Lei.
뇌 사제
How did you get hurt so badly?
왜 이렇게 심하게 다쳤느냐?
Let me see.
어디 보자
Don't bother.
됐습니다
Don't refuse, Lei.
사제, 사양하지 마라
Your wound has a grass spirit in it.
이 상처에 초령이 묻어있어
It'll be hard to stop the bleeding.
당분간 피가 멎기 힘들 거다
I'll go back to Yaoguang Peak and tend to it myself.
제가 스스로 요광봉으로 가서 치료하겠습니다
By the way,
아, 참
please take
이 영주과
this Vermilion Fruit to Baicao Peak.
백초봉으로 전달해 주시길 바랍니다
Lei, don't worry.
사제, 걱정 마
I'll make sure it gets there.
내가 꼭 전달해 주겠다
You're finally awake.
드디어 깼구나
Master, Mr. Dongyang.
사부님, 동양 백부님
Looks like that Vermilion Fruit really works.
영주과가 정말 효과가 있나 보군
It does.
그럼, 효과가 있지
We can rest easy now.
이제 마음 놓이네
Lei has already gone back.
뇌 사제는 이미 돌아갔다
Lifei, are you feeling any better?
좀 괜찮아졌느냐?
Lifei, you owe Qin this time.
려비야, 이번에 네 진 사형 덕이 크다
If he hadn't gathered that Vermilion Fruit,
그가 영주과를 따다 오지 않았다면
you'd be in serious trouble.
네 목숨이 위태로웠을 거다
Lifei's medicine should be ready. I'll go check on it.
사매 약이 다 달았을 테니 제가 가서 확인하겠습니다
There's something we need to ask you.
한 가지 물어볼 일이 있다
You must tell us the truth.
반드시 진실을 말하라
This is important. Don't hide anything.
중요한 일이니 숨기면 안 된다
Was I also tainted by demonic energy,
설마 나도 송풍처럼
like Songfeng?
마기에 감염된 건가?
Lei.
뇌 사제
Today, Master asked where you'd been.
오늘 사부님께서 네 행방을 물으셨을 때
I told him you were in seclusion training.
네가 방에서 수련 중이라 하였다
You were in such a hurry last night.
어젯밤 급히 나가던데
Was it something urgent?
무슨 일이 있었느냐?
Nothing. Thanks for asking.
아무 일도 없었습니다, 감사합니다
If you don't want to say, that's fine.
말하기 싫다면 그냥 넘어가겠다
This healing salve can stop bleeding and draw out poison.
이 복원고는 피를 멎게 하고 독을 없애준다
Cailing, how did you know?
사저께서는 어떻게 아셨습니까?
There's a lot you don't know.
네가 모르는 일은 아직 많다
If there's a chance, I'll tell you everything.
나중에 기회가 되면 하나씩 알려주겠다
A wound like this, from a spirit creature,
영물로 생긴 상처는
needs Elder Dongyang's medicine to heal.
동양 사숙의 약을 써야 완치된다
From what Lifei said, her former master
려비 말에 따르면 그 아이 예전의 그 사부가
was an expert
고수일 뿐만 아니라
and
게다가
had to go into hiding for some special reason.
특별한 사정으로 은거할 수밖에 없었다네
Skilled in sealing techniques
봉인술에 능통하시고
and quite knowledgeable about talismans as well.
부적에도 조예가 깊으시다는데
Alright.
이러지
After I find out which scumbag
내가 먼저 어떤 놈이
hurt Lifei,
려비를 해쳤는지 알아낸 뒤
I'll make a trip to Qingqiu myself.
직접 청구로 가보겠다
Don't mention this to anyone
이 일은 밝혀지기 전까지
until we know more.
남에게 함부로 말하지 마라
Don't worry.
걱정 마라
I brought Lifei to Wuyue Court.
려비도 내가 무월정으로 데려온 아이니
I'll make sure she's safe.
당연히 지켜줄 거다
Look at you.
대단하네
I'm telling you,
있잖아, 그 진양령 조카가
Qin treats Lifei differently from everyone else.
려비를 다른 사람과 대하는 태도가 다르다
Don't practice for the next few days.
요 며칠 수련하지 말고
Get some rest.
푹 쉬어라
And don't worry about the kitchen.
주방 일도 신경 쓰지 말고
Let them fast for a while.
그들 벽곡 수련이나 하게 하라
I heard Lifei got through that
소사매가 이번에 위험을 면한 건
because Qin brought her the Vermilion Fruit.
진 사형의 영주과 덕분이라며
Lifei, Qin gives you treasures
소사매, 진 사형이 보물도 주고
and medicine.
영과도 줬는데
You might have to marry him
평생으로
to pay that back.
갚아야 할 판이군
Simo, since you like Qin so much,
사묵 사형이 진 사형을 그렇게 좋아하시면
why don't you take that honor?
그 좋은 기회를 넘겨줄게요
Qin is a model disciple of Wuyue Court.
진 사형은 무월정의 모범이시다
How can you joke about that?
함부로 농담하지 마라
The incense is lit, and the bed is made.
향도 피우고 침대도 펴놨으니
Let Lifei rest.
소사매 편히 쉬게 하라
Was there really a demon spy back then?
설마 그때 정말 마족 간첩이 숨어 있었다고?
What do demons even look like? Uglier than the ones in storybooks?
마족은 대체 어떻게 생겼을까, 그림보다 더 추할까?
Who's there?
누구야?
Darn it. Nightmare spell again.
이런, 또 염술이군
Stay calm through all changes. Keep your spirit steady and your mind clear.
만변유정, 신이기정
A heart that is clear like water, and the water is the heart.
청심여수, 청수즉심
Break!
파!
Who are you?
너는 누구냐?
What is Qingcheng to you?
청성과 무슨 사이냐?
Ouch, let go.
아파, 아파요
Don't be afraid.
무서워 마라
Which peak are you from?
너는 어느 봉의 제자냐?
What technique did you just use?
방금 쓴 공법은 무엇이냐?
Sir,
선, 선배님
I'm from Zhuiyu Peak.
저는 추옥봉 제자고
That was the Earth-Shattering Turtle Technique
방금 쓴 공법은 사부님께서 가르쳐주신
my master taught me.
석파천경 거북술입니다
Turtle Technique?
거북술이라고?
It's Five Turtles Technique.
그건 오귀술이라고 한다
Then I misremembered.
제자가 기억을 잘못했습니다
That name is so hard to remember.
정말 기억하기 힘든 이름이네요
Wonder who came up with it.
누가 지었는지 모르겠네요
That person is always reckless.
그 사람은 늘 제멋대로 굴지
Why are you here so late at night?
한밤중에 왜 여기 왔느냐?
Well,
저기...
my master sent me to Baicao Peak to pick up some medicine.
사부님께서 저보고 백초봉에 약을 가지러 가라고 하셨는데
My cultivation is shallow.
제가 수위가 얕아서
With the wind and fog, I lost my way.
바람도 세고 안개도 짙어 길을 잃었습니다
Sir,
선배님
I'm in a hurry.
제가 아직 할 일이 있으니
I'll be going.
먼저 가 보겠습니다
That man had a long beard and looked fierce!
그 사람 수염도 길고 엄청 사나웠습니다
He immediately asked me
저를 보자마자
what Qingcheng was to me.
청성과 무슨 사이냐고 묻고
His... His glare alone
그 눈빛이
could have burned right through me.
저를 꿰뚫어 버릴 것만 같았습니다
From what you're saying,
그렇게 말하니
that old man was probably my senior brother,
그 사람은 아마도 내 사형인
Cuixuan.
취현 장로인 것 같네
Elder Cuixuan?
취현 장로요?
I thought he was in seclusion.
폐관 수련 중이시라면서요
Who's Qingcheng?
청성은 누구예요?
His enemy?
그분 원수인가요?
Don't talk about things you don't know.
모르는 일은 함부로 입 밖에 내지 마라
Remember,
기억해라
don't use the Five Turtles Technique in front of outsiders.
앞으로 오귀술을 남들 앞에서 함부로 쓰지 마라
And lately, none of you
그리고 최근에 절대
should go wandering around.
밖에 돌아다니지 마라
Master, could the one
사부님, 어젯밤에 소사매를 해친 자가
who attacked Lifei be connected
몰래 잠입한 마족 간첩과 연관이
to that demon spy?
있지 않을까요?
There are so many disciples in Wuyue Court.
무월정에 수많은 제자들 중
Why target Lifei?
왜 꼭 소사매만 노릴까요?
Yeah. Lifei's spirit energy is average,
그러네요, 소사매는 영기도 평범하고
and her cultivation is low. What's the spy after?
수위도 높지 않은데 뭘 바라는 걸까요?
Is he blind?
눈이 나쁜 건가요?
Well, maybe
아마도
he sees me as Wuyue Court's rising star.
제가 무월정의 신진 수재라고 생각할 수도 있죠
Then he's not just blind. He's also an idiot.
그러면 눈만 나쁜 게 아니라 머리도 나쁜 거군
Alright. Let's focus on what matters.
됐다, 본론을 얘기하라
Whoever it is, they easily
그 자식이 이리 쉽게
broke through Zhuiyu Peak's restriction spell
우리 추옥봉의 금계를 뚫고
and located Lifei's room.
정확히 려비 방까지 찾아간 걸 보면
That scumbag knows this place well.
이곳 지리를 잘 아는 놈이 틀림없다
Elder Chongyi!
사숙
Sir, Songfeng has woken up
사숙, 송풍 사제가 깨어났습니다
and identified the demon spy.
그리고 마족 간첩까지 지목했습니다
My master has invited everyone to Wengu Hall for an interrogation.
사존께서 여러분을 문고전으로 불러 함께 심문하시겠답니다
Qin, who's the demon spy?
사형, 그 마족 간첩이 누구였습니까?
Lei Xiuyuan.
뇌수원이었다
It's him!
바로 저자입니다
The day before the incident, he practiced in front of me.
사건 전날 일부러 제 앞에서 수련하고
After he finished, he left the scroll on the training platform.
수련한 뒤 권축을 연공대에 두고 갔었습니다
I picked it up and wanted to return it.
저는 돌려주려고 주웠다가
But out of curiosity, I flipped through it.
호기심에 펼쳐봤더니
Turns out it was demonic arts!
안에 마족 사공이 적혀 있었습니다
Lei Xiuyuan, you plotted against me.
뇌수원, 네가 일부러 계책을 꾸며 나를 모함하다니
How vicious of you!
정말 독하구나
I hurriedly came out of seclusion
본좌가 밤새 폐관을 나온 것은
to find the demonic rot
문파 안에 잠복한
hidden within our sect.
마족 놈을 찾아내기 위함이다
Whether Lei Xiuyuan has done anything improper
뇌수원이 전에 이상한 짓을 한 적이 있는지는
is a matter of our sect's safety.
문파의 안전과 관련된 일이니
You must speak everything you know.
너희는 아는 대로 모두 얘기하거라
Elder Cuixuan,
사백님
Lei Xiuyuan
뇌수원은
has repeatedly broken Zhuiyu Peak's restriction spell.
여러번 추옥봉의 금계를 뚫은 적이 있습니다
Master,
사존님
on the night Jiang Lifei had the accident at Yuelian Pond,
강려비 사매가 월련지에서 사고가 났던 날
Lei was also there.
뇌 사제도 그곳에 있었습니다
Seems a bit too coincidental.
확실히 우연치 않은 일입니다
It wasn't Lei Xiuyuan.
뇌수원이 아닙니다
Lifei, you never saw that person.
사매, 그 사람을 보지도 못했는데
How do you know it wasn't him?
어떻게 아니라고 단정하느냐?
Lei Xiuyuan did meet me in private a few times,
뇌수원은 확실히 사적으로 저와 몇 번 만났었지만
but he never meant me any harm.
저를 해치려는 기색은 전혀 없었습니다
My master opened my sea of mind.
사부님께서 제게 식해를 열어주셔서
If anyone had ill intent, I would've sensed it.
상대방이 악의가 있다면 분명 알아차렸을 겁니다
Songfeng,
송풍 사형
you said
뇌수원이
Lei Xiuyuan was practicing on the platform the night before the accident.
사건 전날 연공대에서 수련했다는데
What time was it?
몇 시였는지 기억하십니까?
Around the Xu hour.
술시였을 것이다
Are you sure?
확실합니까?
Lifei, what are you trying to say?
려비, 대체 무슨 말을 하고 싶은 거냐?
Lei Xiuyuan couldn't have been at Yaoguang Peak during the Xu hour.
뇌수원은 술시에 요광봉에 있을 리 없습니다
He didn't leave Zhuiyu Peak until the Mao hour.
왜냐하면 묘시에 방금 추옥봉에서 떠났고
Thick fog and long roads lie between the two peaks.
두 봉우리 사이는 안개가 짙고 길이 멀어
Even with his cultivation,
그의 수위으로면 왕복으로
it takes four hours to go back and forth.
두 시진이 걸립니다
So by the time he got to Yaoguang Peak,
그래서 그가 요광봉에 도착했을 땐
the Xu hour would've long passed.
술시가 훨씬 지났을 겁니다
Am I right?
맞지?
Yes.
그래
I don't remember clearly!
잘 기억나지 않는다
Besides, that's just your one-sided story.
게다나 너 한 사람 말만 믿을 수 없다
Maybe you have some old ties with Lei Xiuyuan
네가 뇌수원과 옛정이 있어
and are covering for him.
일부러 감싸는 게 아니냐?
Zhaomin can testify.
소민 사저께서 증명해 줄 수 있습니다
Zhaomin,
사저
you saw him that day, too, didn't you?
사저도 그를 봤었잖아요
Songfeng, I know you lost to Lei,
송풍 사제, 넌 비록 뇌 사제한테 패배하였지만
but win or lose, it's the way of things.
승패는 흔한 일이니
Don't take it too much to heart.
너무 마음에 담아두지 마라
You wretch! Are you falsely accusing him
멍청한 것, 네가 질투심에
out of jealousy and spite?
함부로 모함하는 게냐?
I'm not! It's Lei Xiuyuan!
모함 아닙니다, 뇌수원이 맞습니다
He broke through the third level in just three days.
그가 사흘 만에 삼 층의 경계를 뚫었으니
He must've been secretly practicing demonic arts!
분명 마공을 몰래 수련했을 겁니다
Metal Spirit Root? Gifted?
금영근이고 뛰어난 천부고 모두 가짜고
He's probably the demon spy!
그가 마족의 간첩일 겁니다
True or not, I'll find out with one test.
맞는지 아닌지는 내가 한번 시험해 보면 알 것이다
Zuo Qiu's seal?
좌구의 봉인이구나
Mr. Zuo?
원장님
If Lei Xiuyuan were of demon kind,
뇌수원이 만약 마족이라면
he would never have made it out of the Danxue secret realm.
단혈비경을 나오지도 못했을 겁니다
Cuixuan, let's leave it here.
사형, 여기까지 하지요
Cuixuan, he's someone Mr. Zuo Qiu protects.
사형, 좌구 선생이 지키는 제자니
He's probably fine.
문제는 없을 겁니다
We need to focus on finding the real demon spy.
빨리 마족 간첩을 찾아내는 게 중요합니다
Otherwise, more disciples will get hurt.
아니면 얼마나 많은 제자가 다칠지 모릅니다
That could become a serious problem.
큰 문제가 될 수도 있습니다
Alright. You may go.
됐다, 다 내려가라
As for the one who falsely accused a fellow disciple,
동문을 모함한 자는
he will have his cultivation stripped and be expelled.
수위를 폐하고 무월정에서 쫓아낸다
Master. Master.
사존님
Have mercy, please.
용서해 주십시오
Master, have mercy!
사존님, 용서해 주십시오
I was wrong.
제가 잘못했습니다
I propose we move next year's Achillea Bead Tournament
나는 내년 시초주대회를
up to next month.
다음 달로 앞당겨 개최하려 한다
First,
첫째로는
it will help us identify talents to face the Sea Calamity.
해운을 대응할 인재를 가려내고
Second,
둘째로는
it will let us probe the disciples
각 봉 제자들의 내막을 살펴보아
and root out the demon spy.
마족 간첩을 색출하기 위함이다
Any objections?
사제들, 이의 있는가?
What's the Achillea Bead?
시초주가 뭡니까?
It's a heavenly treasure Elder Cuixuan found
시초주는 취현 사백께서 삼백 년 전
in an ancient secret realm 300 years ago.
상고 비경 중에서 얻은 천지기보라
It was formed from a thousand-year-old achillea plant.
천 년이 된 시초가 응결되어 생긴 것이다
They say its spirit energy is incredible. It strengthens spirit meridians
듣기로 영기가 대단하여 영맥을 강화하고
and boosts cultivation.
수위를 높여준단다
So what's the Achillea Bead Tournament?
그럼 시초주대회는 뭡니까?
Elder Cuixuan holds a combat tournament
사백께서 다들 수련에 힘쓰게 하려고
every three years to encourage us to cultivate hard.
삼 년마다 투법대회를 여시고
The winner can absorb the Achillea Bead's spirit power
우승한 자는 시초주의 영기를 흡수해
to boost their cultivation
수위를 높이고
and also enter its illusion
시초주 환경 속으로 들어가
to seek an answer
자신이 가장
to the one question they most want to know.
알고 싶은 답을 찾아볼 기회가 생긴다
It can talk?
그것이 말도 할 줄 압니까?
No. It's more like a connection.
말하는 게 아니라 일종의 감응이다
In ancient times, achillea was often used for divination.
시초는 고대부터 길흉을 점치는 데 쓰였고
A thousand-year-old achillea is said to understand the ways of heaven.
천 년이 된 시초는 더욱 천기를 통달하여
It's profound beyond words.
신묘하기 그지없다
Like our master's turtle shell?
그 영감의 거북 등껍질처럼 말입니까?
Since it's for divination,
점술이니까
I could ask it where Master is.
그거로 사부님의 행방을 물어볼 수 있겠네
I said no, and that's final!
안 된다면 안 되는 거다
Don't bring this up again!
앞으로 다시는 이 일을 꺼내지 말거라
Master, I want to win the Achillea Bead Tournament.
사부님, 저 시초주대회에서 우승하고 싶다고요
Wouldn't that bring honor to Zhuiyu Peak?
저희 추옥봉 명예를 높이는 일이잖아요
Just give me a few magic treasures.
보물 몇 개만 주세요
No need. Really, no.
필요없다, 정말 필요없다
We don't need you bringing honor to us!
추옥봉은 네가 명예를 높여줄 필요가 없다
Listen up,
알려주는데
just go through the motions. That's all!
얌전히 참가만 하고 와라
I think it's worth a shot.
한번 도전해볼 만한데요
Nonsense!
도전은 무슨, 도전!
Master!
사부님
Just stay alive.
살아있는 게 최고다
I...
저...
Food and drink are what matter most!
잘 먹고 마음 편히 잘 사는 게 진리다
- But I... - Enough!
- 저한테... - 됐다
No, wait.
아니
- Go away. - Ma...
- 비켜 - 사...
Master!
사부님
Winning is a good thing, isn't it?
이기는 게 뭐가 나쁘다고
Why are you leaving?
왜 피하는 건데
Why did Master rush off like that?
사부님께서 왜 급히 가셨느냐?
Did you make him angry again?
또 화나게 했느냐?
No, I didn't.
아닙니다
I just told him
저는 그냥
I wanted to win the Achillea Bead Tournament.
시초주대회에서 우승하고 싶다고 했더니
Then he blew up.
엄청 화를 내시더라고요
Master means well.
사부님도 너를 위해서 그런 거다
This tournament is said to be for selecting vanguard fighters
이번 대회는 해운을 대응하기 위해
to face the Sea Calamity.
싸움에 나갈 인재를 가려내는 자리란다
Sea Calamity?
해운이요?
That great disaster
오백 년마다
that comes every 500 years?
찾아오는 그 재앙 말입니까?
It's more than a disaster. It's an apocalypse.
재앙일 뿐만 아니라 세상이 멸망할 대재앙이다
Five hundred years ago, the Sea Calamity struck.
오백 년 전 해운이 닥치고
Giant waves flooded Guixu.
큰 파도가 귀허로 역류하고
Demons across the seas invaded and slaughtered countless lives.
해외 마족들이 틈타 동쪽으로 쳐들어와 많은 사람을 죽여
The immortal sects of the Central Plains were destroyed.
중토 선문들이 한순간에 궤멸했고
Wuyue Court was nearly wiped out as well.
무월정도 거의 전멸할 뻔했다
Elder Cuixuan and Elder Guangwei were badly wounded.
취현, 광미 사백님들도 중상을 입어
They spent centuries recovering.
수백 년 동안 요양하셨다
Our master barely survived.
우리 사부님께서 겨우 살아남으셨으니
So he's wary of that apocalypse
당연히 그 대재앙을 두려워하시고
and treats it like a threat.
긴장하시는 거지
No wonder Master reacted so strongly.
그러니까 사부님이 그렇게 화가 나신 거군요
But if the Sea Calamity really comes,
하지만 정말 해운이 닥치면
as cultivators, we can't escape it.
저희 선문 제자들은 피할 수 없잖아요
We'll have to face it anyway.
그때 가면 어차피 맞서 싸워야 할 텐데
That's not for you to worry about.
그래도 네 차례는 안 온다
The spy trying to harm you hasn't been caught yet.
널 해치려는 간첩도 아직 못 잡았으니
Just
너는
focus on your training at Zhuiyu Peak.
추옥봉에서 수련이나 하거라
Jiang.
강 사매
This is essence-nurturing water my master made.
이건 사부님께서 만든 증원수다
It regulates your breath and strengthens your vital energy.
영기를 다스리고 원기를 굳혀주며
It'll also help you recover.
회복에 도움이 될 거다
Thanks, Qin.
고마워요, 사형
You found me the Vermilion Fruit
영주과도 찾아주시고
and gave me this magic medicine.
영약과 보물까지 챙겨주시니
If there's ever anything I can do for you,
앞으로 도움이 필요하시면
just say the word.
꼭 말해주세요
Actually,
사실
the first time I saw you at the academy,
처음 서원에서 사매를 봤을 때
you left a deep impression on me.
인상이 깊었어
I'm really glad you came to Wuyue Court.
네가 무월정에 오게 되어 정말 기쁘다
Lifei, I...
사매야, 나...
I'm really happy, too.
저도 기뻐요
Qin,
사형
you're kind and experienced.
사형은 마음도 착하고 경험도 많으시니
Do you know any way to win
시초주대회에서 우승하는
the Achillea Bead Tournament?
방법이 없을까요?
You want to win?
우승하고 싶냐?
Then I'll help you.
사형이 도와줄게
Really?
정말요?
Come on, let's talk it through.
자세히 얘기해 주세요
You're not fully healed,
상처도 아직 낫지 않았는데
yet you insist on entering the tournament.
굳이 이 대회에 참가하려는 건
Is it for Jiang Lifei?
강려비를 위해서냐?
Yes.
예
The one who harmed her hasn't been found.
그녀를 해치려는 자를 아직 찾지 못했으니
I can't rest easy.
마음이 놓이지 않습니다
Do you know about the Sea Calamity?
해운에 대해 들어봤느냐?
Five hundred years ago,
오백 년 전
my master, the sect leader of Wuyue Court,
나의 사존 무월정 장문 진인과
and so many fellow disciples
그 많은 형제들이
sacrificed their lives to hold the East Sea
목숨을 바쳐 동해에서 피를 흘리며 싸워
and protect the Central Plains.
간신히 중토를 지켜냈단다
Now, as the leading immortal sect,
지금 무월정은 선문의 우두머리로서
Wuyue Court will once again be at the forefront against the Sea Calamity.
반드시 해운을 대응할 주력이 되어야 한다
By then, you, as one of our finest disciples,
그때 너는 나의 제자 중 최고로서
will stand with me against the demons.
나를 따라 마족과 목숨 걸고 싸워야 한다
You have Jiaping's talent
너는 가평처럼 천부적인 재능을 갖고 있고
and a stronger will than his.
또 가평보다 마음이 더 굳센
You are a genius of a generation.
세상에 드문 천재다
Don't let an obsession with love cloud your duty to the greater good.
정에 매달려 대의를 놓치지 마라
Are you really entering the tournament?
정말 대회에 나가려고?
For Jiang Lifei,
강려비를 위해
you almost got branded a demon spy.
이미 마족 간첩으로 몰릴 뻔했는데
Are you planning
나중에
to die for her next time?
그녀를 위해 목숨까지 바칠 셈이냐?
None of your concern.
걱정하지 않으셔도 됩니다
You...
너...
Jiang Lifei.
강려비
Mr. Dongyang, what are you doing?
동양 백부님, 뭘 하시는 겁니까?
You'll know
시합 때가 되면
when the tournament comes.
알게 될 것이다
You're mostly healed.
상처는 거의 나았지만
But your heart meridians are damaged.
심맥에 손상을 입어
To fully recover,
완전히 나으려면
you'll need another Vermilion Fruit.
영주과 하나를 더 먹어야 한다
Elder Dongyang.
사숙
Sir, I'm here to pick up medicine for Lei.
사숙, 뇌 사제 약을 가지러 왔습니다
I'll get it.
내가 가져오마
Thank you.
수고하십니다
Yue.
악 사저
What... what happened to Lei Xiuyuan?
뇌수원은 어떻게 된 겁니까?
Was he hurt by Songfeng?
지난번 송풍에게 다친 상처 때문입니까?
Lifei, you're so innocent and charming.
려비 사매는 정말 순진하고 귀여운데
You bewitch without even trying.
무의식적으로 사람을 홀리는군
Why pretend you don't know?
알면서 왜 묻는 거지?
Two bottles for external use. One for internal.
두 병은 바르게 하고 한 병은 복용해야 한다
Since it's a spirit creature wound,
영물에게 입은 상처이니
don't let it get wet.
물이 닿지 않도록 하라
And he shouldn't circulate his energy or practice these next few days.
요 며칠은 수련하는 것도 삼가라
Otherwise, the wound will worsen,
아니면 상처가 악화되어
and the pain will be unbearable.
견디기 힘든 고통을 겪을 거다
I'll keep it all in mind. Thank you.
알겠습니다, 감사합니다
Wounded by a spirit creature?
영물에게 입은 상처라...
Sir,
사백님
was the Vermilion Fruit I took
제가 저번에 먹은 영주과
gathered by Lei Xiuyuan?
뇌수원이 따다 준 거예요?
Since you don't care about him,
마음이 없다면
leave Lei alone
더 이상 엮이지 말고
and let him focus on his cultivation.
뇌 사제 수련을 방해하지 마라
Or it would hurt both of you.
서로 해를 끼치는 일이 될 테니
I thought Qin saved me?
진 사형께서 저를 구해주셨다면서요
I'm not sure of the details.
그 사정은 나도 잘 모르겠다
Maybe they both wanted to save you.
두 사람이 모두 너를 구하고 싶었지만
But Lei was the one who dove in to get the fruit.
물속으로 들어가 약을 딴 사람은 뇌수원이었겠지
Tongzhou?
동주
I'm fine.
저는 괜찮습니다
Take care of yourself at Xingzheng Hall.
성정관에서 몸 잘 챙기십시오
I'll come see you when I have time.
시간 나면 찾아뵙겠습니다
Your Highness, Her Highness is here again.
왕야, 군주께서 또 오셨습니다
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
Sit.
앉아라
Have Mingli show you around in a bit.
이따 명례를 시켜 구경시켜 줄게
I've been busy lately.
요즘 일이 바쁘구나
Tongzhou, I don't need anyone to accompany me.
사촌 오라버니, 괜찮습니다
Just let me stay by your side.
오라버니 곁에만 있게 해주시면 됩니다
Mr. Xuanshan has me in seclusion for training. You can't follow.
백부님께서 폐관 수련하라고 하셨는데 네가 따라다니면 어떡하냐
Besides, it's improper for us to be alone together.
게다가 남녀가 따로 있는 건 풍습에 맞지 않다
Then let's just get married.
그럼 혼인하면 되잖아요
Once we're married,
혼인만 하면
no one will have anything to say.
아무도 수군거리지 않을 거예요
Lanya, I've told you many times.
란아, 내가 몇 번 말했느냐?
We're cousins. I won't marry you.
우린 남매 사이니 혼인할 수 없다고
But His Majesty said
하지만 황 오라버니께서
our engagement would go ahead as planned.
저희 혼약은 그대로 이행할 거랍니다
Lanya, I can give you anything else.
란아, 다른 일은 내가 만족시켜 줄 수 있지만
Just not this.
이것만은 안 된다
I have to go see Mr. Xuanshan soon.
나는 잠시 후 백부님을 뵈러 가야 하니
Sit here for a while.
여기서 쉬고 있거라
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
Deities above.
신이시어
I know
저는 평생
I'll never see him again in this life.
영원히 그를 다시 못 볼 거라는 걸 압니다
But I can't stop thinking about him every day.
하지만 매일 참지 못하고 그를 그리워하고 있습니다
Even though he's probably forgotten me,
비록 그는 저를 잊었겠지만
I'm willing to trade my years
제 수명을 바쳐서라도
for the prince's happiness and safety.
소왕야가 원하는 걸 이루고 즐겁게 지내길 바랍니다
Duantu?
단도?
Are you telling me to go find him at Duantu?
신이시어, 단도로 가서 찾으라는 겁니까?
Thank you so much.
감사합니다, 정말 감사합니다
Qin.
진 사형
Longyuan Manifestation?
용연화형
Lei,
뇌 사제
you haven't even been here a year,
입문한 지 일 년도 안 됐는데
yet you've already mastered such fierce sword arts.
이렇게 매서운 검술을 익혔다니
Where there are people, there are conflicts.
사람이 있는 곳에는 시비가 따르기 마련이니
Without the ability to protect yourself,
자신을 지킬 실력이 없다면
you're bound to be set up.
간사한 자에게 해를 입기 마련입니다
Lei, you misunderstand.
뇌 사제, 오해다
But you were there both when Lifei was attacked
려비 사매가 다쳤을 때와
and when Songfeng fell into demonhood.
송풍 사제가 마도에 빠졌을 때 모두 네가 현장에 있었으니
I'm just worried you might've been tainted by demonic energy.
사형은 너도 마기에 감염될까 염려되고
Just being cautious.
화근을 막으려 한 것이다
If you suspect me,
만약 저를 의심하시면
you can just report it to Elder Cuixuan.
사형께서는 취현 장로께 고하시면 됩니다
I'll see it through and get to the truth.
저는 끝까지 진실을 밝히는 데 따르겠습니다
And
그리고
when I find the one who harmed Lifei,
제가 진정 려비를 해친 진범을 찾게 되면
regardless of who it is,
그가 누구든
I won't let them off.
가만두지 않을 겁니다
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival♪
♪수많은 겁난도♪
♪The lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge. Past the pagoda♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나♪
♪In fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어 가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니♪
♪Startling the whole world♪
♪온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
Don't let the wound get wet.
물에 닿지 않도록 하라
And he shouldn't circulate his energy or practice these next few days.
요 며칠 수련하는 것도 삼가라
Otherwise, the wound will worsen,
아니면 상처가 악화되어
and the pain will be unbearable.
견디기 힘든 고통을 겪을 거다
♪In fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds. Break through the waves♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고 거친 파도를 깨부수니♪
♪The heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과♪
♪And falling petals♪
♪지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪
The Achillea Bead Tournament will span three days.
이번 시초주대회는 사흘 동안 진행한다
May all disciples from every peak give their full effort.
각 봉 제자들은 전력을 다하고 숨김없이 임하고
Prepare yourselves for the coming Sea Calamity.
곧 다가올 해운에 대비할 준비를 하여라
All disciples from the sixteen peaks must participate.
십육 봉 제자들은 모두 참가할 것이고
By the end of the Wu hour,
오시 말까지
sixteen winners will advance to the second round.
승자 열여섯 명을 가려 제2차로 진출하게 된다
From the Wei hour onward, the top eight will be decided.
미시부터 팔강 제자를 선발할 것이다
To ensure each peak has a disciple in the second round,
모든 봉에서 한 명씩은 제2차에 진출하게 하기 위해
Zhuiyu Peak gets a bye in the first round.
추옥봉은 제1차 시험을 통과시키겠다
- Really? - That's great!
- 정말? - 너무 다행이다
Cuixuan, isn't that unfair?
사형, 너무 불공평한 거 아닙니까?
Baifu, have you lost your mind?
백 씨, 미친 거 아닌가?
Under Cuixuan's leadership, Wuyue Court
우리 무월정은 취현 사형의 이끌림 아래서
has never been unfair.
언제 불공평한 적이 있었나?
How could it be unfair?
불공평할 리가 없지
We're about to start. Stop your nonsense.
곧 시작할 테니 잡소리 말고
Shut your mouth.
입이나 닥치고 있게
Let the tournament begin!
대결을 시작하겠다
Amazing.
대단하네
As expected of Qin.
역시 진 사형이야
Incredible.
정말 대단해
Lifei, hurry.
사매야, 얼른 가자
Lei has already won six matches.
뇌 사제가 이미 6연승을 거두었대
Everyone says it's spectacular.
다들 재미있다고 하더라
If we're late, we'll miss the best parts.
늦으면 재밌는 시합을 놓치겠다
Lei is really impressive.
뇌 사제 정말 대단하네
- As expected of Lei. - Yeah.
역시 뇌 사제야
Absolutely amazing.
정말 대단해
Lei is incredible!
뇌 사제 정말 대단하네
Were you two really fellow disciples?
정말 너와 동기 맞냐?
What are you implying?
무슨 뜻입니까?
Nothing. Just that
아니다, 그냥
talent levels differ, and quality varies.
역시 자질에는 높고 낮음이 있는 법이군
You...
아니
Lifei.
사매
The name tag for your second-round opponent is out.
제2차 대결 상대가 나왔다
Who am I facing?
저 누구랑 대결합니까?
Deng Xiguang.
등계광
Deng?
등 사형?
That's Elder Baifu's top disciple.
그분은 백부 장로의 수제자신데
Deng Xiguang?
등계광
It's okay, Lifei.
괜찮다, 사매야
Just going through the motions.
형식적으로 참가만 해도 괜찮다
Remember my name! I'm Deng Xiguang!
내 이름을 꼭 기억하여라, 나는 등계광이다
I have an idea.
나한테 방도가 하나 있지
As the Sage taught,
성인께서 말씀하시길
extend the respect and care
남의 노인도 나의 노인을 대하듯 아끼고
you show your own family to others as well.
남의 아이도 내 아이 대하듯 아끼랬다
As your senior,
나는 사형으로서
I'll go easy on you
몇 수 양보해 주마
and let you lose with dignity.
그래도 체면은 챙겨서 지게 해주겠다
Deng, you're such a good person.
사형, 정말 착하시네요
Please accept my bow.
제가 절 한 번 올리겠습니다
Lime powder?
석회 가루야?
Sorry, Deng.
죄송해요, 사형
I'm too busy training
제가 매일 수련하느라
to wash my clothes.
빨래할 시간도 없네요
It's all dust. See?
먼지 좀 보세요
See?
이것 좀 보세요
As the Sage taught,
성인께서 말씀하시길
winning unfairly is dishonorable, but yielding shows...
속임수로 이긴 건 영광이 아니고 양보해 주는 건
virtue!
덕이라 하였다
Did he faint from shock?
놀라서 기절한 거야?
- How did he faint? - He just fainted?
- 왜 기절한 거지 - 기절한 거라고?
No way.
설마
That's one way to do it.
그것도 방도지
Didn't see that coming.
생각도 못 했네
I won!
내가 이겼다
Which peak is she from?
어느 봉 제자냐?
Yeah.
그러게
Is she from Zhuiyu Peak?
너희 추옥봉 제자 아니냐?
I don't know. I don't recognize her.
저로 몰라요
I don't know her!
모르는 사람이에요
Outrageous!
말도 안 된다
Can such a despicable win even count?
사형, 이런 비열한 수법을 써도 우승한 겁니까?
Baifu, watch your words.
백 씨, 말조심해
What do you mean, despicable?
비열한 수법이라니
That's called strategy and quick thinking.
이건 지혜를 써서 상황 맞게 대처하는 거다
Magic is a contest of both power and strategy.
법술이라 하면 법만 겨루는 게 아니라 술도 겨뤄야지
Don't you understand?
알지도 못하면서
She truly has her master's style.
그 사부에 그 제자지
Yes. She's my disciple. What of it?
그래, 내 제자다, 어쩔 거냐?
As expected of your disciple.
친제자 맞군
The top eight are set. Tomorrow will determine the top four.
팔강이 가려졌다, 내일 사강 승자를 뽑는다
Jiang Lifei versus Tang De.
강려비 대 당덕
Qin Yangling versus Cheng Feng.
진양령 대 성봉
Yue Cailing versus Ban Tou.
악채령 대 반두
Lei Xiuyuan versus Wu Jiahui.
뇌수원 대 오가휘
All participating disciples
모든 참가 제자들은
have taken enough demon-purging water.
제마수를 충분히 마셨다
Any who have secretly practiced demonic arts
몰래 마공을 수련한 자는
will lose control and be exposed tonight.
오늘 밤 모습을 드러낼 것이다
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난도 향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어 가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪